《絕命律師》前情提要
Previously on Better Call Saul...
你為什么要跟我作對
Why were you working against me?
你不是個真正的律師
You're not a real lawyer.
現在就剩我一個人了  那一千五都歸我
And now that I'm doing the job alone, I get the full $1,500.
我能弄到更多藥
I can get more pills.
要當罪犯
If you're gonna be a criminal,
先得做點功課
do your homework.
感謝您沒有卷款潛逃
Thanks for not heading to the Bahamas with this.
-你在做什么呢  -"正確的事情"
- What are you doing? - "The right thing."
無論如何  你現在還生氣嗎
Whatever it was, did you get it out of your system?
不生氣了
Yep, all gone.
磯鷂渡一案
The Sandpiper case?
哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所接不下
It's getting too big for HHM.
你是什么意思
What are you talking about?
我是說在圣達菲有一間
I'm talking about there's an office in Santa Fe
寫有你名字的辦公室
with your name on it.
奧馬哈
品質保證
兩百年歷史
♪朋友你好♪
♪Well, hello, there♪
♪好久不見♪
My, it's been a long, long time
♪你問我最近如何♪
♪How am I doin'?♪
♪我覺得還湊合♪
♪Oh, I guess that I'm doin' fine♪
辛那邦[美國烘焙連鎖店]
♪時光飛逝♪
♪It's been so long now♪
你想讓鏡子里的這個人為你服務嗎
♪感覺卻像♪
♪And it seems that♪
♪只是昨日♪
♪It was only yesterday♪
♪時光飛逝♪
♪Gee, ain't it funny♪
♪真是可笑♪
♪How time slips away♪
♪我該走了♪
♪Gotta go now♪
♪改日再見♪
♪Guess I'll see you around♪
♪卻不知何時能再見♪
♪Don't know when, though♪
*不知我何時回到鎮上*
*Never know when I'll be back in town*
晚安  女士們  路上小心
Good night, ladies. Get home safe.
♪但請記得♪
♪But remember♪
♪我曾說過♪
♪What I tell you♪
♪總有一天♪
♪That, in time,♪
♪你會付出代價♪
♪you're gonna pay♪
♪時光飛逝♪
♪And it's surprising♪
♪真是驚訝♪
♪How time slips away♪
不不不
No, no, no, no!
該死
God damn it!
不  別這樣
No! Oh, c-come on.
來人啊
Somebody!
緊急出口  打開這扇門會觸發警報
警方會被通知  如果你必須撤離
緊急出口
向下扳開門  觸發警報
索爾·古德曼到此一游
絕命律師
第二季 第一集
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗 喵球球 joy_bwl 人妻 肉松
翻譯  克里斯 上癮的楊愛菜 西陵折枝 酸奶
校對  喃喃 君君
時間軸  夢龍  今  姜姜  喃喃
后期  潤天使小新     總監  喃喃
他來了
Ah, here he is.
太棒了
Oh, great.
吉米  真準時  很高興能見到你
Jimmy, right on time. Good to see you.
-你好  霍華德  -你們好
- Hello, Howard. - Hey. Hi.
這位是詹姆斯·麥吉爾  這位是克利福德·梅因
James McGill, Clifford Main.
叫我吉米就好  幸會  克利福德
Just "Jimmy." And it's a pleasure to meet you, Clifford.
幸會  我們知道你為磯鷂渡一案做出的努力
Likewise. We know all about your work on Sandpiper.
是團隊成果
Well, it's a group effort.
哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的人
I mean, the folks at HHM
做得非常好
are just knocking it out of the park.
如果沒有你  也就不會立案
Well, you know, the case wouldn't exist without you.
當然
Absolutely.
一旦他加入你的團隊
Once you get him on your team,
就知道我為什么叫他"騙子查理"了
you'll know why I call him "Charlie Hustle."
吉米  他們是我的律師
Jimmy, these are my associates --
布萊恩·阿楚萊塔和艾琳·布里爾
Brian Archuleta and Erin Brill.
-很高興認識你們  -幸會
- Nice to meet you both. - It's great to meet you.
非常抱歉
I hate to do this,
但我能跟韋克斯勒小姐單獨說句話嗎
but, um, could I borrow Ms. Wexler for a moment?
失陪一下
If you will excuse us?
失陪
Pardon me.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我
I just, um
聽著  是這樣
Listen, here's the thing.
如果我接受這份工作  是否意味著我倆...
If I take this job, does that mean the two of us...
我是說...
I mean, uh...
是否意味著...
Does it mean, uh...
什么  你到底想說什么
What? What -- what the hell is this?
如果我今天接受戴維斯梅因律所的工作
If I take this job today, with Davis and Main,
是否意味著你和我...
does that mean that you and me...
能成嗎
Is this -- is this gonna happen?
吉米  我...
Jimmy, I...
我...
I...
這兩件事沒有任何聯系
One thing has absolutely nothing to do with the other.
完全無關嗎
Nothing at all.
無關
No.
當然無關了  為什么會有呢
Of course not. Why would it?
好吧
Great.
非常抱歉
Oh, sorry about that.
我想說  衷心感謝你們
Listen, I just wanted to say thank you sincerely
考慮我
for your interest in me.
這是我的榮幸
It's a honor to be considered,
但是現在  尤其是現在
but at this time...at this time,
我想我還是不加入了
Um...I'm gonna have to take myself out of the running.
非常感謝
Thanks.
謝謝你  霍華德
Thank you, Howard.
吉米
Jimmy.
挺快啊
That was quick.
不收費
No charge.
幫我想想
Help me out here.
我是在做夢
Did I dream it?
還是我辦公桌上真的有一百六十萬美元現金
Or did I had 1.6 million dollars on my desk in cash?
地球上沒人知道我們有這錢
No one on god's green earth knew we had it.
我們可以五五分成
We could have split it 50/50.
我們本可以每人帶八十萬美金回家  不用交稅
We could have gone home with $800,000 each, tax-free.
你想說什么
Your point being?
我們為什么沒那么干
Why didn't we?
我記得你說  要做對的事
I remember you saying something about doing the right thing.
你想知道我為什么沒拿那錢嗎
You want to know why I didn't take that money?
你是在問這個嗎
Is that what you're asking?
沒錯  我是想問那個問題
Yeah, that's what I'm asking.
對我個人來說  別人雇我干活
Me, personally -- I was hired to do a job.
我干完了  就結束了
I did it. That's as far as it goes.
是的
Yeah.
我知道是什么阻止了我
Well, I know what stopped me.
聽好了
You know what?
它再也不會阻止我了
It's never stopping me again.
你們好  女士們
Chao chi c'ung, ladies.
你們好
Chao chi c'ung.
阮女士  外面天氣很好
Mrs. Nguyen, it's beautiful day out there.
你偶爾也要出去一下
You should get out of this place once in a while, you know.
扔扔飛盤什么的  散散心
Throw a Frisbee, have some fun.
我要經營生意
I have a business to run.
不  不對
Uh, no.
是生意在"經營"你呢
The business is running you.
聽我的
Listen to me.
你以后會感謝我的
You'll thank me later.
只有顧客才能享用黃瓜水
Cucumber water for customer only!
詹姆斯·麥吉爾律所
喂  是我啊
Hey! It's me!
天啊  聽得見嗎
Geez. Hello?
嘿
Hello?
是我啊  我買了新車
It's me. I got a new car.
你喜歡嗎
You like it?
我們不能開這個去碰面
We're not taking that to the meet.
那我們怎么去呢
How are we gonna get there?
我來開車
I'll drive.
開我的車
My car.
為什么
Why?
這樁生意要求克制
This business requires restraint.
但這車恰恰相反
That is the opposite of restraint.
但是我喜歡它
But...I like it.
我是說  我為它自豪
I mean, I'm proud of it.
好的
Good.
那你一個人自豪去  別拉著我
Then you be proud of it on your own time, but not with me.
我拒絕上車
I'm not getting in that.
好吧  那  那就別上車了
Okay. Then -- then don't.
實話說  你也沒干什么
Honestly, uh, you don't really do anything.
你只是站在我背后而已
I've been paying you the salary of three people
我就要付你三人份的報酬
to just stand behind me.
而且  而且最近幾次交易
You know? And -- and these-- these last few deals --
這個叫納喬的  他都是一個人來的
This Nacho fella, he's been coming alone.
如果他不需要帶人
I mean, if he doesn't need backup men,
那我為什么要帶你呢
then, I mean, why do I need you?
我應該一個人去
I should just go alone.
不然我就浪費錢了
I'm throwing -- I'm throwing away money.
跟扔垃圾堆里一樣
Just tossing it away. Into the trash.
隨你怎么辦
Look, you do whatever you want,
但是我建議你  如果沒有人跟著你
but I'm advising you -- do not go to that meet
別一個人去
without someone watching your back.
是啊  你當然會這么說了
Yeah, well, of course you're gonna say that.
你才不想失去這份輕松賺大錢的工作
I mean, you don't want to be out of this easy-peasy job.
不過抱歉  這個肥差
Well, I'm sorry, but this is the gravy train,
馬上就要溜走了
and it's leaving the station right now.
所以最后一次機會
So last chance.
上車
All aboard.
我說真的  最后一次機會
Seriously, last chance.
我數到十  然后我就...
I'm gonna count to, say, 10, and then I'm...
好  那行
All right, then.
你的服務到此為止了
Your services are no longer needed!
你好
Hola.
老頭子沒來
No old guy?
怎么  他是扭到腰了還是怎么了
What, did he break a hip or something?
是啊
I know, right?
不過不是的  我們...
Yeah, no, we, uh...
我們散伙了
we -- we parted ways.
產生了一些分歧
Yeah, saw things differently.
所以...  你懂的
So... You know how it is.
這車不錯
This is interesting.
是啊  你喜歡嗎
Oh, yeah. You like it?
我能看看嗎
Can I take a look?
隨意參觀  請上車
Be my guest. Get in.
進去看看
Check it out.
真不錯
Impressive.
謝謝  上車看看  感受下真皮
Thank you. Get in. Feel the leather.
是H2型
Yeah, it's a H2.
新款才下線
Brand-new off the line.
比H1型輕巧但車身稍長  車頂更高
Slimmer than the H1 but longer, more height.
這車相當不錯
Yeah, it's a honey.
V8引擎  325馬力
V-8 engine, 325 horsepower,
三區空調系統
tri-zone climate controls.
即使坐在車里的姑娘
So you can have a girl in a bikini
一個穿著比基尼而另一個穿著大衣
and another in a parka,
也都會感覺很舒適
and they're both gonna be comfortable.
帶著兩個姑娘  開著越野車
You're running around with two girls in your S.U.V.,
真是爽翻天了
you'd be really comfortable, huh?
是啊
Oh, yeah. Yes.
我去點下錢
I'm gonna count this quick.
去吧  別數錯了
Do your thing. Make sure it's right.
新墨西哥州  機動車輛管理局
車輛登記證書
好了
Okeydokey.
沒問題
We are good.
跟以前一樣
Uh, same as before.
沒開過封的
Uh, still factory-sealed.
跟往常一樣  你盡管點一下
And, as always, you're welcome to count them.
我相信你
I trust you.
很好  謝謝
Great. Thank you.
下次見
See you next time.
你好
Hello?
是的
Yes.
不  抱歉
Uh, no. Sorry.
但是...  對  我是詹姆斯·麥吉爾
But -- Yes, this is James McGill,
但我不做律師了  所以...
but I'm no longer a lawyer, so...
對  不做律師了  再見
That's right -- not a lawyer. Bye.
這就是中年危機的表現嗎
So, this is what a midlife crisis looks like?
不是中年危機
Not midlife crisis.
是醒悟
Clarity.
中年醒悟
Midlife clarity.
醒悟
Clarity?
那你給我解釋清楚為什么要放棄
Clearly explain to me why you walked out
你這輩子最好的工作機會
on the best job opportunity of your life.
進池子里  我就告訴你
Get in the pool, and I'll tell ya.
進池子里
Get in the pool?
對  來啊
Yeah. Come on.
去紀念品商店買件泳衣
Just pop in the gift shop and buy a bathing suit --
連體的就行  不用太花哨
get a one-piece, nothing fancy.
水溫正好  二十八度
The water is perfect. It's 82 degrees.
點一杯喝的
You can order a drink.
然后嘗嘗這的薯片蘸醬
And you got to try this crab dip.
你為什么要這樣
Why are you acting like this?
我沒怎么樣
I'm not acting like anything.
我只是  終于下定決心做我自己
I just... finally decided to be me.
還好嗎康普森先生  要再來一杯嗎
Everything okay, Mr. Cumpston? Would you like another drink?
不用了
Uh, I'm good with this.
你給我聽好  康普森先生
I'll tell you what, Mr. Cumpston.
如果你真想談談  我在酒吧等你
If you really want to talk, I'll be in the bar.
我不會等太久
Not for long.
羅蘭多
Hey, Rolando.
結賬
Check.
"不干法律了"是什么意思
What do -- What do you mean "Quit the law"?
就是不干了  就這么簡單
I quit it. Simple as that.
感謝你的解釋  吉米
Oh, well, thanks for explaining, Jimmy.
-現在清楚多了  -伙計
- It's super-clear now. - Hey, buddy?
這里是印錯了嗎
Uh, is that a misprint right there?
一定是印錯了
It's got to be, right?
-陳年藍寶石嗎  -是的
- The Zafiro Añejo? - Yeah.
沒印錯  真的
That's correct, actually, believe it or not.
老天爺  一杯龍舌蘭要五十美金嗎
Holy shit. A $50 shot of tequila?
-值嗎  -當然
- Is it worth it? - Apparently.
不過也看個人喜好了
I mean, it's kind of a personal-choice kind of thing.
這輩子一定得嘗嘗五十美金的龍舌蘭
Well, I can't die without trying a $50 shot of tequila,
兩杯  純的
so, uh...two -- dos -- neat.
能跟房費一起結  對嗎
And, uh, we can charge that to the room, can't we?
不  不用  我們
No, we can't. We...
我來付
I am paying.
給他一杯這里最便宜的
And he will be having a shot of your well brand,
我要一杯普通紅酒
and I'll have a glass of your house red.
我們有解百納  比諾和西拉
We have a Cabernet, a Pinot, and a Syrah.
都可以
Whatever. Dealer's choice.
有酒精就行
Something with alcohol.
沒問題
You got it.
吉米  在西塞羅市發生了什么
Jimmy... did something happen in Cicero?
為什么西塞羅市一定要有事發生
Why did something have to happen in Cicero?
因為我跟你說戴維斯梅因律所時
Because when I talked to you about Davis & Main,
你都準備好接受那份工作
you were ready to take the job.
現在你回來了  突然要放棄法律工作
Now you're back, and you're suddenly quitting the law,
在酒店騙喝昂貴的酒
cheating hotels out of expensive liquor,
帶一個奇怪的尾戒
wearing a weird pinkie ring?
怎么  加入黑手黨了嗎
What, are you in the mafia now?
還問我們有沒有未來
Asking if we have a future.
到底怎么回事
I mean, where did that come from?
我不知道  只是
I don't know. I just...
西塞羅跟這沒關系
Well, Cicero has nothing to do with it.
是我的人生
It's my whole life.
從查克讓我來到阿爾布開克開始
Well, my life since Chuck made me come to Albuquerque.
自從我來到這兒
Ever since I got here,
我所做的一切都是為了讓查克高興
all I've done is try to make Chuck happy,
使出渾身解數來討好查克
bend over backwards to please Chuck.
查克  查克  查克  再也不這樣了
Chuck, Chuck, Chuck. Well, no more.
你放棄從事法律  這不正是查克想要的
You quitting the law -- isn't that exactly what Chuck wants?
誰在乎呢
Who cares?
這是為了我自己  好嗎
This is for me, okay?
因為各種錯誤的原因  我開始從事法律
I-I got into the law for all the wrong reasons.
我相信自己的直覺
I'm trusting my instincts.
我的才華還是發揮在別處比較好
I think that my talents are better spent elsewhere.
在哪兒  漂在別人的泳池里嗎
Where? Floating in somebody else's pool?
吉米  你是個了不起的律師
Jimmy, you're a great lawyer.
為什么要放棄
Why give that up?
也不是說我不享受做律師
I'm not saying it didn't have its moments,
只是我所喜歡的事
but the stuff I liked about it --
說服別人  讓別人信服
selling people, convincing people --
不當律師也可以做到
I don't have to be a lawyer to do that.
還有  我知道別人怎么看我
Besides, people tell me how they see me,
他們并不把我當律師
and it's not as a lawyer.
這是您要的酒
All right. Here you go.
謝謝
Thank you.
還需要什么隨時叫我
Lemme know if I can get you guys anything else, okay?
波比  怎么樣  伙計
Bobby, what up, brother man?
謝謝
Oh, thanks.
做空
Short it.
做空  把那垃圾做空
Short it. Short that shit.
那支股毫無價值  沒有前途
That stock is useless. It's got no legs.
就像馬戲團的怪咖  但毫無樂趣
It's like a circus freak minus the fun.
那支更糟糕  誰跟你推薦的
And that one's even worse. Who's giving you these?
幫我一個忙  拿個枕頭
Please do me a favor. Take a pillow,
放在那支股票的臉上
put it over that stock's face
直到你聽到垂死呻吟
until you hear the deathbed queef.
-是個賠錢貨  -好吧
- It's a loser. - Okay, so...
如果你不做律師  要做什么
if you're not gonna be a lawyer, then what?
漂著等磯鷂渡的錢到手嗎
Float around and wait for your Sandpiper money to roll in?
-不  -那可能要好幾年
- No. - That could take years.
磯鷂渡跟這沒關系
Sandpiper has no bearing on this at all.
這個有前途
Yeah, it's got legs.
那好  有什么計劃
Okay, then, what's the plan?
用開放的心態迎接未來
To be open to the universe.
那就是沒計劃
Okay, so no plan.
隨心所欲
Just walk the Earth,
像《低俗小說》結尾的朱爾那樣嗎
like Jules at the end of "Pulp Fiction"?
無論未來給我什么
Look, whatever the universe presents,
無論有什么樣的機會  我都會接受
whatever opportunity arises, I will take it.
-無論什么樣的機會嗎  -是的
- Whatever opportunity? - Yeah.
戴維斯梅因律所不是一個機會嗎
Wasn't Davis & Main an opportunity?
是非常好的機遇  但你放棄了
It's a great opportunity, and you're walking away from it.
不是他  不是那個人...
Not him, not the guy who...
拒絕前難道不該至少試一下這份工作嗎
Look, shouldn't you at least try the job before you say no?
浪費所有人  包括我自己的時間
And waste everyone's time, including my own?
金  謝謝你的關心  但那不適合我
Kim, I appreciate your concern, but it's not for me.
我不想要
I don't want it.
吉米  你記得你為司法考試學了多久
Jimmy, do you remember how long you studied for that bar?
你有多用功
How hard you worked?
所有努力都付之一炬嗎
All that effort, you're just gonna toss it away?
這是沉沒成本謬誤
That's the Sunk Cost Fallacy.
認為已經花了很多時間  金錢和精力的事就應該繼續下去
什么
W-- The what?
沉沒成本謬誤  是賭徒行為
The Fallacy of Sunk Cost -- it's what gamblers do.
賠了夫人又折兵
They throw good money after bad
以為自己運氣好  能回本
thinking they can turn their luck around.
我已經花了這么多錢和時間
It's like, "I've already spent this much money or time --
無論怎樣我都得繼續
whatever, I got to keep going!"
但游戲最后是沒有回報的
No, there's no reward at the end of this game.
你錯了
You are making a mistake.
我知道你錯了
I know you're making a mistake.
我這些年一直在做所謂正確的事
I've been doing the "right" thing for all these years now,
但我落得什么下場  糟透了
and where has it gotten me? Nowhere.
抱歉  我不...
I'm sorry. I don't...
我沒點
It's not my thing.
我不懂
I don't get it.
-我就是不懂  -這才是對的事
- I just don't get it. - It's what's right for me.
扯淡
Donkey balls.
純粹扯淡  伙計
Pure donkey balls, dude.
華爾街是廢柴待的地方
Wall Street's for suckers.
誰吃飽了撐的想去那兒啊
Who needs that aggravation?
如果股神巴菲特不非得待在那兒
If the the Oracle doesn't have to live there,
那我肯定不去
then I sure as hell don't.
我坐馬桶上  用手提電腦就能交易
I can make a million-dollar stock trade on my laptop
一百萬美元的股票
sitting on a toilet.
麥德斯  傳說能點石成金的人
就像麥德斯往我王座上拉金磚
Like Midas, shitting gold bricks on my throne.
所以斯皮爾格曼和戴伊奇才這么想要我的生意
That's why Speigelman and Deitch want my business so bad.
我是大金主
I'm a golden God.
我當然記得  誰會忘記那種事
Look, of course I remember that. Who forgets a thing like that?
那種屁話是被壓抑的弱勢群體的憤怒
That fart had the anger of a repressed minority community.
你當著誰的面放這種屁
You fart like that in someone's face,
他下輩子準得紅眼病
you're gonna give them pinkeye for life.
聊得很愉快  伙計
Good convo, bro.
下次再說  兄弟
Till next time, brutha-man.
跟我來
Come with me.
-什么  -來就好  相信我
- What? - Just come on. Trust me.
你要干什么
What are you gonna do?
你想明白我說的話
You want to understand what I'm talking about?
就跟我來
Follow my lead.
伙計  能幫我們解決一個賭局嗎
Hey, buddy, could you settle a bet for us?
-我怎么  -抱歉
- I what? - Uh, sorry.
我并不想搞得像我在偷聽
I don't want to make it sound like I was eavesdropping,
但我不小心聽到了
but I kind of was.
我們聽到你說股票的事
Uh, we heard you talking about stocks.
那么問題來了
Yeah, so, question --
你能不能解決我和我妹妹的爭論
if you could settle a debate between me and my sister.
算了吧  我們不該打擾這位...
Uh, you know what? We probably shouldn't be bothering this --
我們一般不麻煩別人  是吧
We wouldn't normally do this -- right?
但我們需要一個專家
But we need an expert.
他聽起來好像很懂行
This guy sounds like he knows his stuff.
沒錯  你說
Yeah, go.
行  問題是這樣的
Okay. Here's the question.
在股票市場中
Uh, when it comes to the stock market,
允許個人投資的數額
is there, like, a financial limit
有沒有限制
to how much a person's allowed to invest?
限制
A limit?
沒  沒限制
No. No limit.
我就知道  那如果是遺產呢
Knew it. Oh, even if it's an inheritance?
比如  要交遺產稅之類的
You know, with, like, inheritance taxes and whatnot?
同樣沒有
Nope. Same.
太棒了  謝謝  伙計
That's -- oh, fantastic. Thank you, buddy.
聽到沒  沒限制  跟你說了我們能全投進去
See? No limit. Told you we could invest it all.
而且這也是明智之舉
And it's a smart move, too.
全存銀行里  不行
Sticking it all in the bank? No.
沒錯  你可以投資所有的錢
Yeah. You can... invest all your money.
但確保要分散投資
Just make sure you diversify.
沒錯  分散投資
Yeah. Diversify.
那...  你得...
That's -- You got to --
你說的"分散投資"是什么意思
Oh, hey, um... what do you mean, "diversify"?
分散投資就是
Well, diversify is --
你聽過一句名言
Y-you know that saying,
"雞蛋別全放在一個籃子里"  是吧
"Don't put all your eggs in one basket," right?
一個道理
Same principle.
沒錯  完全說得通  謝謝
No, it makes complete sense. Thank you.
如果你能告訴你要投多少錢
Now, if I had an idea of the money we're talking about --
大致數目  我可以教你精明地分散投資
ballpark -- I could give you examples of smart diversification.
好吧...
Yeah, um...
聽著  我們父親那邊的一位叔叔最近去世了
Look, an uncle on our father's side recently passed,
給我們留下了大約一百四十萬的遺產
and he left us somewhere in the neighborhood of $1.4 million.
不是我這人貪心  但我覺得
And I don't mean to be greedy, but I think,
如果我們現在明智地投資
if we invest it smart now,
我們可以將它翻兩倍  三倍
we could double it, triple it --
甚至可以將這筆錢翻四倍  對嗎
we could quadruple the whole inheritance, right?
在我看來
In my opinion?
財富屬于有膽量的人  兄弟
Fortune favors the bold, man.
如果你們有時間和我喝一杯
Now, if you guys are free to join me for a drink,
我可以給你們簡單參謀一下
I can give you a quick consult.
沒關系  我們自己能行
That's all right. We were gonna do it ourselves
用那種在線經紀網站就行
through one of those online brokerage websites.
我們打算選個經典點的  比如...
We're just gonna pick, uh, a classic, like --
好像是叫藍籌股
I think they're called blue-chip stocks?
對  對  你們自己完全沒問題
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you can totally do it yourself.
就挑那些可靠的
Shoot for the tried and true.
當然  你們可能會把錢投到興登堡號
'Course, you might be putting your cash in the Hindenburg,
德國大型飛艇  運營后第二年燒毀
意大利游輪  1956年與另一船只相撞沉沒
安德烈亞·多里亞號
the Andrea Doria,
美國電影  上映后票房慘敗
或者  《聯邦大蠢探》上
uh..."Corky Romano."
不是嗎
Right?
它們當時看起來都可靠極了  可結果呢
They all seemed rock-solid beforehand, but then...
是啊  不怎么好
Yeah, not good.
不怎么好  沒錯
Not good, yeah.
那要如何區分呢
So, how do you know?
那就需要我們這種人出場了
Well, that's where someone like myself comes in.
資深的理財經理
Proven track record as a wealth manager.
我能規避風險  又敢于冒險
I take calculated but aggressive risks
因為我想抓住轉瞬即逝的機遇
'cause I want to catch lightning.
而我確實能
And I do.
基本上我就是一臺印鈔機
Practically a money-printing machine.
聽上去不錯
That sounds good.
印鈔機
A money-printing machine.
聽著  那邊有個小隔間
Listen, there's a little booth over here.
方便說話  我們可以談談  不用承諾什么
There's some privacy. We can talk. No obligations.
我們可以...  隨便談談這件事
We can just -- just rap about this a little bit.
-好啊  也可以  -好嗎
- Yeah, I guess. - Yeah?
你說呢  妹妹
What do you say, sis?
我們能談談嗎
Can we just talk?
滑步舞啊
Electric slide on in there.
我們就簡單談兩句  不是...
And we'll just rap a little bit. It's no --
順便說一句  我叫肯
My name's Ken, by the way.
維克多  中間是"K"
Uh, Viktor, with a "K."
好啊  中間是"K"的維克多
Cool. Viktor with a "K."
這位迷人的女士呢
And this lovely lady is?
我叫...吉賽爾  吉賽爾·圣·克萊爾
It's...Giselle. Giselle Saint Claire.
好極了
Ah, lovely.
請坐  我不會咬人的
Please, sit. I won't bite.
那么  中間是"K"的維克多和吉賽爾
So, Viktor with a "K" and Giselle
異域風情的名字
exotic names.
是荷蘭人名
They're Dutch.
準確地說  是布爾人
Well, Boer, to be precise.
我們父親家那邊來自南非
Our...father's side of the family is from South Africa,
漢弗萊叔叔就是在那去世的
which is where Uncle Humphrey passed away.
南非
South Africa.
那里盛產美女啊  不是嗎
They grow them beautiful down there, right?
查理茲·塞隆  還有你
Charlize Theron. And you.
我其實沒在那待過  不過希望以后能去
I've never actually been, but hope to go someday.
聽著  等我為你們理財結束
Tell you what, by the time I'm done with you two,
你們可能連私人飛機都有了
you might be taking your own private jet.
好極了
Nice.
不好意思  我們都坐這兒了
Excuse me. Hi. Uh, we are sitting here now,
所以我們需要一份酒單  如果你...
so, uh, we could use a wine list, if you get a chance --
你喜歡喝龍舌蘭嗎
Hey, uh, are a tequila fan?
喜歡
Yes.
你想喝嗎
You down for that?
你喝過陳年藍寶石嗎
You ever try Zafira Añejo?
沒喝過  不過我喝什么都行
No, I have not, but I'm down for whatever.
來三杯她說的那個
Three of whatever she just said.
-沒問題  -好的
- You got it. - All right.
那么  股票市場  很棒的投資途徑
So, stock market. A great investment.
現在正是入市的好時機
And you're picking the right time to jump in.
你為什么要聽我的  我是個白癡
Why do you listen to me? I'm an idiot.
談論他的豪車  談論...
And talks about his cars, talks about --
-他有多少輛車  -我覺得...
- How many cars did he have? - I don't think --
-那沒道理啊  -沒錯  肯
- It doesn't make sense. - That's it, Ken.
這是酒保送給你們的
Compliments of the bartender.
她覺得你們可能想留個紀念
She thought you might want a souvenir.
天啊  我們把整瓶酒喝光了嗎
Oh, my God. Did we drink the entire bottle?
還沒呢  沒喝光
Not yet, we didn't.
-來  -干杯
- Boom. - Hey, cheers.
我覺得我們該結賬了
Uh, I think we're ready for the check.
不  這是最明智的方式
No, really, it's the smart way to go.
好吧  不過說清楚
Okay. But, so, to be clear,
你直接從我們的賬戶取錢來投資
you take the money directly from our account and invest it.
-分散投資  -分散投資
- Diversify. - Diversify it.
接著所有紅利和利潤
And then all the dividends and all the profits
還有...我們給你的錢都會回到我們的賬戶
and the...what-have-you comes back into our account.
沒錯  說得太對了
Boom. Absolutely.
你們還會拿到一份詳細說明
And you'll get a detailed statement
上面寫著你們的錢漲了多少
showing you how much your money is growing --
當月最旺的股票等等
biggest bulls of the month, et cetera.
肯  兄弟  就這么辦吧
Ken, buddy... let's do this.
好  簽在這兒  中間是"K"的維克多
Great. Right there, Viktor with a "K,"
吉賽爾  等下你也簽
and, Giselle, you are next.
好刺激啊
This is so exciting.
很高興能為你們服務
Folks, it's been a pleasure.
-我來買單  -我可不會讓你買單
- Oops, I got that. - Can't let you do it, son.
等等  什么  肯  你人真好
Wait. What? Ken, you are the greatest.
-謝啦  -小事一樁
- Thank you. - No problem-o.
聽著  這會是你們做的最棒的決定
Hey, this will be the best decision you'll ever make.
我也覺得
Oh, I believe it.
好了  我們就不繼續打擾你了
All right, well, we should get out of your hair.
-沒錯  -等等  別急
- Yeah. - Oh, wait, wait.
這...是給你們的
This...is for you.
上面有我所有的聯系方式
Now, that's got all my contact info.
有問題或者有事都可以打給我
Call me anytime with questions or anything at all.
肯
Ken.
再見  記得打給我
Bye. Call me, guys.
-再見  -快來攔著我們啊
- Bye. - Try and stop us.
棒
Wow.
太棒了
Just wow.
我...
What I--
這帳沒錯吧
Is this right?
沒錯  先生
Yes, sir, it is.
快走快走
Go, go, go, go, go!
陳年藍寶石
Zafira Añejo!
他會追出來的
He's gonna come out.
不
Oh, no.
我都沒看那張紙
I didn't read the fine print.
-等等  -爽
- Wait. - Yeah!
天吶
Holy crap.
真不敢相信...
I can't b--
你刷完能借我刷嗎
Can I borrow that when you're done?
不行  太惡心了
No, that's gross.
怎么會惡心
H-how is it gross?
我們身上的病菌早就混到一起了
Our germs have already intermingled.
這是我的牙刷  情況不一樣
It's my toothbrush. It's different.
怎么不一樣了
Why is it different?
就是不一樣
Because.
牙齦經常出血  就會有...
You know, gums bleed, and there's --
會有唇皰疹病菌  各種食物以及古怪的...
there's cold sores, all sorts of food and weir--
讓我看看  來嘛
Let me see that. Come on.
什么  不
What? No!
來嘛  我現在就刷
Come on! I'll do it right now.
-我才不管  -我得刷牙了
- I don't care. - I need to brush my teeth.
我沒其它牙刷了  怨不得我
I don't have an extra. It's not my problem.
沒關系  我用這個
That's fine. I got this.
很好  這樣我不介意
Good. I'm fine with this.
我也不介意
Yeah, me too.
等會看我用什么當牙線
Wait till you see what I floss with.
該好好留著這個
That's a keeper.
謝啦  中間是"K"的維克多
Thank you, Viktor with a "K."
如果我們每晚都那樣  不是很好嗎
Wouldn't it be great if we could do that every night?
是啊  是很好
Yes, it would.
可惜...
But...
我們不能那樣
we can't.
我知道
I know, yeah.
只是說說嘛  如果可以  一定會很棒
But I'm just saying, if we could, it would be great.
但我知道我們不能
But I know we can't.
糟了  今天我不能遲到
Oh, crap. I can't be late today.
霍華德要分配任務
Howard is doling out assignments,
最后進門的人
and the last one through the door
只能去復審文件
could get stuck in doc review.
你要出去嗎
You got somewhere to go?
是啊  我要去一個地方
Yeah. Uh, yeah, I got somewhere.
好了嗎
You good?
好了
Yeah. All good.
你是丹尼爾·沃莫爾德嗎
Daniel Wormald?
我是貝克警官  這位是薩克斯頓警官
I'm Officer Baker. This is Officer Saxton.
好的  請進吧
Yeah, please. Come on in.
進來吧  在這里
Come in. It's over here.
看看他們做了什么
See what they did?
全都被盜走了
I mean, all gone.
一個不剩啊  就...
All of them, just --
什么一個不剩
Uh, what's all gone?
我有  我之前有一套棒球卡片的珍藏
I have -- I had a baseball-card collection --
一整套呢...全被盜走了
a major collection -- all stolen.
很遺憾聽到這消息
Oh, sorry to hear that.
有很多人知道你收集棒球卡嗎
Uh, was it common knowledge that you have baseball cards?
不  也不算多
No, not really.
所以  沒什么人格外覬覦你的卡片
So, nobody in particular you can think of wanting them?
沒有  我想不出來  沒有
No. Not that I -- No.
他們怎么進來的
How'd they get in?
那邊的后門
Uh, the back door over here.
我回家吃午飯的時候發現它開著
It was open when I came home for lunch.
本來是鎖上的
I mean, it was locked,
他們肯定是撬了鎖還怎么的
but they must have jimmied it open or something.
你覺得大概是什么時候的事
At what time, uh, you figure this happened?
我8點15分去上班  12點半回家吃午飯
I left for work at 8:15, came home for lunch at 12:30,
然后立馬就報警了
and called you immediately.
有沒有丟失其他物品
Was anything else taken?
現金  不少現金
Cash -- a fair bit. Uh, um...
有多少
How much cash?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
先關注最重要的東西好嗎
You know, let's focus on what's important here, you know?
我只關心我的棒球卡
All I really care about are my baseball cards.
我有一張托普斯家的米奇·曼托新秀卡
You know, I have a Topps Mickey Mantle rookie card
那是獨一無二的
that's irreplaceable.
那是鑄幣級的
It's a mint,
定位比例正面為60/40  反面為90/10
60/40, 90/10 on the reverse.
我可以列舉出很多特色
I can go on.
我所有的卡片都是小心存儲的
All my cards are in top-loaders,
如果把它們拿出來風吹日曬的
but if they're taken out and exposed to the elements,
或者是彎折了  天吶可千萬別
I mean, or creased, God forbid,
短短幾秒鐘  就會貶值一大截
I mean, you're looking at a 9-point downgrade in a matter of seconds.
我知道像這樣的案子
I understand the first 48 hours
案發后四十八小時是破案的黃金時期
are the most important in investigations like this,
時間過去越久
so the more time passes,
找到失物的可能性就越小
I mean, the less likely we are of a recovery.
所以  時間寶貴啊  兄弟們
So...time is of the essence here, guys.
我們會盡全力幫助你的  沃莫爾德先生
Well, we're gonna help you out the best we can, Mr. Wormald.
很好
Good.
他們還真是把這地方翻了個底朝天
They really tossed this place.
你確定他們不是在找其他東西嗎
I mean, are you sure they weren't looking for anything else?
比如說
Like what?
我不知道  只是問問你的想法
I don't know. J-Just wondering your thoughts.
我猜他們想找更多的棒球卡吧
I assume more baseball cards.
除了鎖在那個盒子里的那些
Did you have more baseball cards
你還有其他棒球卡嗎
than the ones you keep locked in that case here?
有  在后面  好幾千張呢
Yes, in -- in back -- thousands.
但是這些才是極品
But these were the crown jewels over here.
全明星陣容
You know, t-the all-star lineup.
好吧
Right.
怎么了
What?
我只是想理清一下狀況
Just trying to make sense of it.
有什么好理的  不就是
What's to make sense of? I mean, isn't it as simple
小偷來偷棒球卡嗎  多簡單
as the perp was looking for more baseball cards?
或者是嗑藥嗑嗨了
Or hopped up on speed or whatever
瘋了一樣來這掃蕩一通
and went nuts with the vandalism?
是啊  也有可能
Yeah. I mean, that could be.
外面那輛悍馬挺酷的
Pretty sweet Hummer parked in the driveway.
是你的嗎
That yours?
對  是我的
Yeah, that's mine.
租來的
Uh, it's a lease.
價錢特別劃算
Got a great deal on it.
真酷
It's very sweet.
你知道嗎  他們說悍馬
You know, they say Arnold Schwarzenegger
就是為了阿諾德·斯瓦辛格而生的
is the reason that Hummers exist.
我也不知道為什么  他們就這么說的
I don't know how, but that's what they say.
真的啊
No kidding.
你是做什么工作的  沃莫爾德先生
What kind of work do you do, Mr. Wormald?
我是搞IT的
Uh, I work I.T.,
在一家制藥公司上班
uh, for a pharmaceutical company.
哇  搗鼓電腦的
Wow. Computers.
天哪  我就該學計算機的
God, I should've gotten into computers.
-那我也能開那樣的悍馬了  -沒錯
- I'd have that same Hummer. - Yeah, right.
兄弟們  我很高興你們喜歡我的車
Look, guys, I'm glad you like my car,
但我覺得我們現在
but I think we're looking through
重點錯了吧
the wrong end of the telescope here.
最重要的是要找到我的棒球卡
You know, the priority is my baseball cards.
當然
Of course.
好的  我把我的所有藏品列了一份詳細的清單
Yes, now, I have a detailed manifest of my entire collection
高價的卡片旁邊標了星號
and asterisks next to the high-ticket items,
所以很容易就能看出來他們會最先出手哪些
so it's clear which ones they're gonna try to fence first,
因為這些超級超級值錢
'cause they're super, super valuable.
你們需要拿著這份清單去找典當行
So you're gonna want to get this list out to pawnshops,
收藏愛好者  查問所有
uh, collectors, question anyone who's done
有類似前科的人
any sort of crime like this in the past.
那些按常理來說有嫌疑的人
You know, the -- the usual suspects.
我能把名單給你們  好讓你們開始調查嗎
Uh, can I get you the list so you can start investigating?
好的  要是你能給我們列個名單...
Yeah, you -- Yeah, if you could get us that list...
我會...我會打印出來的
Okay, I'll -- I'll print it out.
漢克·阿倫卡  鑄幣級
Hank Aaron, mint.
天  我的德瑞克·基特簽名
God, my signed Derek Jeter.
威利·梅斯  奧皮奇收藏卡
Willie Mays, O-Pee-Chee.
深呼吸  深呼吸
Got to breathe. Just keep breathing.
繼續深呼吸
Keep breathing.
-好吧  -我就說嘛
- Okay. - I know, right?
沒拿走電視機
Left the TV.
-沒拿走電腦  -沒錯
- Left the computer. - Right.
眼前這情況看上去有點不對勁
There's something wrong with this picture.
喂  是我
Hey, it's me.
我又在這個天堂度過了完美的一天
Another perfect day in paradise out here.
我在泳池里
I'm in the pool.
給我回電
Okay, call me.
-你好嗎  -寶貝  吃過中飯了嗎
- How are you? - Hey, babe. Did you get lunch?
我吃了
I did.
我覺得我背上快被曬焦了
You know, I think I'm burning up back here.
真的嗎  你可真走運
Oh, really? Well, you're just in luck.
-瞧瞧我拿了什么  -太好了
- Look what I have. - Oh, hey, great.
你這里都被曬紅了
Oh, yeah, you're all red back here. Yeah.
好爽啊  寶貝
That feels good, babe.
我跟你說過了不要在太陽下待太久
I told you not to spend so much time in the sun.
你就是不聽
You don't listen.
喂  又是我
Yeah, it's me again.
我說話這當兒  離我不到八米的地方
Listen, as I speak, not 25 feet away from me,
我正看著目標
I'm looking at the mark.
喜劇《蓋里爾的島》中的大富翁
想象下豪威爾·瑟斯頓三世和金吉同居后的樣子
Think Thurston Howell III if he shacked up with Ginger.
他渾身上下都是古馳牌的
He's dripping in Gucci.
就好像  我蹲在水坑里
It's like I'm at the watering hole,
我是準備出擊的母獅  看著那頭
and I'm watching the fattest, slowest water buffalo
最肥最遲緩的水牛向我露出了脖子
expose his neck to me, and I'm the lioness ready to strike.
來吧  金
Come, Kim.
加入我吧  加入獅群吧
Join me. Join the pride.
我剛說母獅
Um, I said "Lioness"
是因為狩獵是母獅的活兒
because it's the females who do all the hunting.
只是想準確描述這個物種
Uh, just wanted to be species-accurate,
跟我的性別無關
irrespective of my own sex.
就像《國家地理》上提過的那樣...
It's a National Geographic thing. Anyway...
我掛了
Get out here.
再見
Bye.
圣達菲  新墨西哥州
Santa Fe, New Mexico.
我想知道戴維斯梅因律所的電話
I need the number of a law firm -- Davis & Main.
好的  幫我轉接下
Yeah, you can connect me.
公司用車上有多種選擇
There are a few options on the company cars.
您有空的時候我們可以安排試駕
We can arrange a test-drive whenever you'd like.
公司用車  哇
Company car -- wow.
不管您在哪兒  都能夠
And there's a service that will deliver it right to you,
隨叫隨到
wherever you want.
如果您覺得不滿意
And if you find you're not happy with it,
隨時都能換
it's not a big deal to change it out.
聽上去真是...
That sounds really, uh...
太好了
Yeah.
真有意思
This is, uh, interesting.
如果...
Oh, if, uh...
如果這不符合您的品味
If this isn't to your taste,
我們倉庫里有各種畫作
we have a collection of art in-house
您可自由選擇
you can, uh, choose from.
只要您有空
Anytime you're ready,
我能給您一些樣品供您挑選
I can put together some samples for you to review.
我...不  我就喜歡這個
I-I-I -- No, I like this.
好的  您要是還有別的需要  我隨時效勞
Good. Uh, well, any other needs you have, I'm here to help.
辦公用品  飲食需求...
Office supplies, dietary needs...
有什么指定的食物想放在冰箱里嗎
Anything special you want stocked in the fridge?
要加濕器嗎  這里有點干燥
Uh, maybe a humidifier? Gets kind of dry in here.
奧馬爾  我這人很隨意的
Omar, I-I'm pretty low-maintenance.
好的  如果您有任何需求
Sure. Well, if there's anything you need,
我就在外面
I'm right outside the door.
好
Great.
要是我想起什么的話
If I think of anything.
好
Good.
對了  你覺得...
Hey, do you think, um...
我只是在看這張桌子
I'm just looking at this.
我們有其他辦公桌可以選嗎
D-do we get a choice of desks?
您想要怎樣的
What were you thinking?
能不能...
Is it possible, um...
能用...黃檀木的嗎
Can we do...cocobolo?
黃檀木辦公桌  沒問題
Cocobolo desk? Absolutely.
我馬上去辦
I'll get right on that.
一直開著
不要關
非常歡迎愛好者加入字幕組一起翻譯海外影視劇